William James Keidel

(909) 446-5047 | william.keidel@gmail.com www.github.com/wilyuhm | https://www.linkedin.com/in/williamkeidel

EDUCATION

University of California, Riverside

BS, Computer Science

Riverside, CA

June 2016

SUMMARY

Software Developer and recent Computer Science graduate with 9 months experience working with data collection, database management, API and web-based application development. Experienced in learning new technologies quickly and applying them to projects. Skilled at working with a team in a scrum based Agile development environment.

SPECIAL SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Python, C++, C, HTML, SQL, LaTeX
- Relevant Tools: Django Framework/Rest API, Angularjs, Bootstrap CSS, Linux, Git, JSON/GeoJSON, Amazon AWS, Hadoop
- Relevant Coursework: Databases, Website Development, Artificial Intelligence, Data Structures and Algorithms, Computer Networks

WORK EXPERIENCE

AutoDev LLC Lake Arrowhead, CA
Software Developer March 2016 - Present

- Worked on data collection, analysis, storage, and presenting data to the user in a logical, user-friendly way
- Converted our PHP backend into a Python backend with Django database models, services, and serializers
- Developed a Django Rest API with the Django Rest Framework to serve collected data from our Amazon database
- Designed and implemented a Python Craigslist web crawler which collected information about vehicle transactions, including price and location information.
- Wrote an AngularJS application to give users the ability to browse the database of collected vehicle information
- Gathered experience learning and implementing multiple different technologies (languages, frameworks, etc.)
- Kept well-documented and frequent commits to git for revision history

Redlands Police Department

Citizen Volunteer Park Ranger

February 2015 - Present

Ensure city parks remain a safe environment for park-goers and assist the police department with various traffic duties.

YMCA of the East Valley

Redlands, CA

Redlands, CA

Equipment Engineer I

May 2014 - Present

- Perform general rigging and equipment maintenance for the youth circus program to facilitate daily training
- Promoted from Equipment Engineer III in December 2015

Wray and Associates

San Diego, CA

San Diego Zoo Summer Performer/Puppeteer

May 2016 - December 2016

4 Starr Construction

General Construction

Redlands, CA

August 2013 - October 2014

PERSONAL PROJECTS

- CLcrawler: An individual personal project creating a Craigslist web crawler and statistics generator implemented in Python to
 track individual vehicle prices in specific geographical areas. Created with the dealer, vehicle wholesaler, and private
 consumer markets in mind. Built upon this project further for Autodev LLC.
- UCRInterest: A school group web development project built to be similar to Pinterest using the Codeigniter web framework and Bootstrap CSS

Mar. '17